# Ogundotun Balikiz

## Frontend Developer

in https://www.linkedin.com/in/ogundotunbalkiss/ # https://twitter.com/Balkissty

https://github.com/balkissty

#### **PROFILE**

I am a Frontend developer with expertise in developing responsive websites and proficiently implementing Figma designs. I have a keen interest in acquiring knowledge about the latest technologies, transforming concepts into actuality, and working alongside committed teams to create effective and resilient applications.

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

**Frontend Developer** 09/2022 - 01/2023 Hero Technologies Abuja, Nigeria

• Develop new user-facing features

- Collaboration with team members to ensure technical feasibility of designs
- Build reusable codes
- Working with APIs to ensure interactivity.

**Frontend Developer** 

02/2023 - 05/2023 Nigeria Police Force Central motor Registry ∅ Abuja, Nigeria

05/2023 - 10/2023

Nigeria

- Meeting with development team to discuss user interface ideas and applications.
- Reviewing application requirements and interface designs.
- Identifying web based user interactions.
- Developing and implementing highly responsive user interface components.
- Troubleshooting and debugging application codes.
- Monitoring and improving frontend performances.
- Documenting application changes and developing updates.

Frontend Developer (Contract)

Paritie Dynamic Enterprise Limited *⊗* • Creating reusable and efficient React components to enhance code maintainability

and scalability.

• Building responsive web applications that work seamlessly across different devices and screen sizes.

• version control with Git and efficient collaboration within the development team

#### LANGUAGES

Html	• • • •	Css	• • • • •
Javascript	• • • •	Reactjs	• • • • •
Bootstrap	• • • •	Tailwindcss	• • • • •

#### **PROJECTS**

E-commerce website *\oslash* 

**Central Motor registry** 02/2023 - 05/2023

https://cmris.npf.gov.ng/

Striit App & 2023

Striit is more than just an app to check for available parking spots and bylaw updates. It's a community of drivers and app users helping one another avoid parking tickets, keeping cars safe, and making parking better—together.

## **SKILLS**

## Practical knowledge of Frontend Technologies

Html5, CSS3, JAVASCRIPT, REACTJS, TAILWIND AND BOOTSTRAP CSS

#### **REST APIs**

Experience with REST APIs and third-party libraries

#### **Version control**

Proficient understanding of Git and Github.

## Organizational skill

Planning and ability to work with time

## Collaboration

Strong team spirit

#### **Learning Ability**

Quick and sound learning ability

#### **Adaptability**

Adaptability to environmental condition and technological advancement

## **EDUCATION**

#### **BAgric/Animal Science**

Osun State University

2011 – 2016 Osogbo, Nigeria